<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Shizra Tariq</title>
    <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shizra Tariq</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 13:51:42 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shizratariq.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CV / Resume</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>📄 My Resume You can view or download my latest resume below: 📥 Download Resume (PDF)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracurricular Activities</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/extracurricular/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/extracurricular/</guid>
      <description>Founder – Youth Revamp Organization A student-led initiative focused on youth development, skill-building, and social impact.
Beta – Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador Represented Microsoft Learn on campus by conducting technical workshops and mentorship sessions.
Member – Pakistan Student Federation, MSU Mankato Contributed to organizing cultural and educational events representing Pakistan abroad.
President – Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador Society, KFUEIT Led outreach and engagement activities across campus, promoting technology and career readiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🏅 Awards &amp; Honors</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/awards/</guid>
      <description>Fulbright Scholarship Program 2023 Awarded by: Institute of International Education (IIE), USA
Description: Selected for the prestigious Fulbright Scholarship to pursue graduate studies in the United States.
National Youth Award Nominee Awarded by: Higher Education Commission (HEC), Pakistan
Description: Nominated for excellence in academic and community achievement.
Global UGRAD Program Awardee – Fall 2021 Awarded by: IREX, USA
Description: Selected among 37 female finalists from Pakistan to represent the country in a cultural exchange program in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Goroutines - Channels, WaitGroup, Cancellation</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/docs/goroutines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 13:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/docs/goroutines/</guid>
      <description>If you have rough ideas on how goroutines work but never took the time to learn the idiomatic approach and why we want to run goroutines certain way, this blog will be of help. In this post, I will be summarizing what I have learned from Chapter 8: Goroutines and Channels of the Go Programming Language book as well as The Go Blog on Go Concurrency Patterns.
This blog post will be helpful if you are not familiar with any of the below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a Blog Powered by Hugo to Github Pages w/ Custom Domain via Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/docs/deploy-hugo-to-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 11:42:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/docs/deploy-hugo-to-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post provides a step-by-step guide on how you can create this blog powered by Hugo, configure Github Actions to publish to Github Pages, and link custom domain to your Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide is also available on Youtube &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_QSr2_pxIJs&amp;amp;ab_channel=dhij&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m a Master’s student in Robotics at the University of Minnesota, passionate about developing robotic systems for healthcare. Currently, I’m working on Automated Probe Insertion in the Biosensing and Biorobotics Laboratory under Professor Suhasa Kodandaramaiah. Previously, I worked on robotic surgery for histotripsy, where I used the UR5e robotic arm with ROS2 and MoveIt2 to improve motion planning and ensure collision-free navigation in constrained environments.
Beyond research, I love traveling and fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accurate Subtitle Generation in Videos </title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/subtitle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/subtitle/</guid>
      <description>Implemented a full end-to-end Streamlit pipeline for generating improved subtitles, integrating Whisper transcription, segmentation methods, and FFmpeg-based SRT embedding.
GitHub Repository: View on GitHub
Project report You can view or download the project report below: 📥 Download report (PDF)</description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Autoethnographic Study on Social Media Usage</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/auto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/auto/</guid>
      <description>This project examines my personal interactions with social media through an autoethnographic lens. I documented usage behaviors, emotional responses, and reflections to understand their impact on my life.
Project report You can view or download the project report below: 📥 Download report (PDF)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bionic Arm Equivalent Model Based on IoT and AI Classification</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/bionic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/bionic/</guid>
      <description>Developed a myoelectric, IoT and AI-based bionic arm model that interprets EMG muscle signals to control a 3D-printed prosthetic hand in real time.
Project report You can view or download the project report below: 📥 Download report (PDF)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breast Cancer Detection</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/breast_cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/breast_cancer/</guid>
      <description>Developed a mammography-based breast cancer detection system using multiple machine learning techniques.
GitHub Repository: View on GitHub
Project report You can view or download the project report below: 📥 Download report (PDF)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Assisted Neural Probe Insertion</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/probe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/probe/</guid>
      <description>I developed a computer-vision–based system to detect neural probes, estimate insertion points using 3D calibration with ArUco markers, and guide automated probe placement. I also built the full workflow; from data labeling to trajectory planning, to enable accurate, safe, and repeatable probe insertions.
Project Presentation You can view or download the project presentation below: 📥 Download report (PDF)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/experience/</guid>
      <description>Research Assistant Biosensing and Biorobotics Laboratory, University of Minnesota — Summer 2025–Present
I am developing a real-time computer vision and robotics pipeline for automated probe insertion in the mouse brain to monitor neural activity. My work integrates object detection with keypoint-based pose estimation and Perspective-n-Point (PnP) to recover the full 6-DoF probe pose, while employing CNN-based classification to assess probe bending and stability under challenging visual conditions. Teaching Assistant Carlson School of Management, University of Minnesota — Summer 2025</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Computer Assisted Nueral Probe Insertion 🔗 Developed a computer-vision pipeline to detect the probe shaft and tip, classify bending, and enable real-time feedback during insertion. Prepared datasets, trained segmentation and ResNet models, and analyzed performance issues such as dataset imbalance and visibility challenges. Designed and implemented a 3D calibration system using ArUco markers and camera parameters to convert 2D detections into 3D insertion coordinates. Built the workflow for automated probe insertion, including insertion-point estimation, reference-frame creation, trajectory planning for robotic control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/skills/</guid>
      <description>👨‍💻 Programming Languages Python C/C++ C# JavaScript MATLAB SQL 🧰 Tools &amp;amp; Frameworks Git GitHub Linux CUDA PyTorch OpenCV PyBullet JIRA 📜 Certificates Python for AI Convolutional Neural Networks SQL Machine Learning 🌟 These skills reflect my background in robotics, AI, and software engineering. Check out my projects to see them in action!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super resolution and Object detection on Remote sensing imagery</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/super_resol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/super_resol/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced object detection accuracy by improving input image resolution.
GitHub Repository: View on GitHub
Project report You can view or download the project report below: 📥 Download report (PDF)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the Future: Open Source vs. Proprietary AI</title>
      <link>https://shizratariq.github.io/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shizratariq.github.io/test/</guid>
      <description>This project systematically compared open-source and proprietary AI models using real-world academic test cases to evaluate their accuracy, relevance, and practical performance. It produced benchmarking reports, analysis, and a seminar presentation to help stakeholders understand which models best fit their needs.
Project report You can view or download the project report below: 📥 Download report (PDF)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
